With the 62nd pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Buffalo Bills select
David Igmanos,
DV Ohio State.
>> Trade alert, the Bills move up four
spots into the bottom of the second
round to draft quarterback Davidson
Ignosen out of Ohio State. Welcome into
our NFL draft special alongside a voice
of the Bills, Chris Brown. I'm Mattie
Glab. Iben Osen is 6'2, 191, long frame,
long arms, a speedster, ran a 445
40, and knows how to disrupt routes.
Physicality is his game. He's going to
get in your face and bat balls down. Why
does drafting a quarterback in the
second round make sense for Buffalo?
Well, I think it was a sneaky need for
the Bills because if you look at their
current roster right now, the only
players on their roster who got on the
field last season and played cornerback
for this team were Max Haristen and
Christian Benford. Duro they picked up
in free agency obviously played corner
somewhere else. Atlanta he's projected
as a possible nickel corner. So outside
you really have no depth because Dorian
Strong is coming back from a neck
surgery. His future is uncertain as far
as an NFL career is concerned. There is
no determination on his future playing
career as of right now. So he's a major
if with a capital I. You don't have
anyone else. You needed to fortify the
depth at the cornerback position and the
Bills felt it necessary to trade up to
get Igbonosen here and you know he's
reunited with Jordan Hancock his former
Ohio State teammate. So, I I think it
was a need that they had to address at
some point in the draft. They choose to
do it at the bottom of round two.
>> They trade their 66th overall pick. That
was their third rounder and their 182nd
pick. That's the sixth rounder to the
Broncos for 62 to get into the bottom of
the second round and pick Ignosen. As
you watch his highlights, he flies
around the field. He's quick. that 44540
and is a physical cornerback press man
is his type of game.
How will his physicality fit in to the
quarterback's room in Buffalo?
>> Well, I mean, he's 6'2, 189, so he's a
little narrowframed and I think he does
have to add strength and a little bit of
bulk uh cuz he's kind of long and lean,
but that's what the Bills like. They
like length and height uh for corners
that play outside for them. Benford's
6'1. Harrison, I think, is an even six
foot, but he's long limbmed. And so too
is Igmanosen. I mean, he's got 33 inch
arms. I mean, that's like offensive line
arm length. So, they like long, tall
corners outside. He fits the bill there.
I think he's got to get a little bit
bigger and stronger. You know, run
support. Setting the edge out there on
the outside is something that he's still
learning to be more consistent with in
terms of his game. But you're right
about him being a press man corner. He
likes getting in the face of wide
receivers. He trusts his hip flip and
ability to turn and plaster in man
coverage and will jockey for position
all the time. And I think the word to
use for him in terms of plant and drive,
he's twitchy. Okay?
>> Like he can stick his foot in the ground
and go in the other direction at the
drop of a hat. So when that receiver is
stemming his route, he can plant his
foot or on a comeback, he can plant his
foot, jump the route, make the int. um
ultra competitive player. He's the
youngest of four boys, six kids total in
his family. We're talking about the
number one high school recruit in the
state of New Jersey. Yeah.
>> When he came out for college, went to
Old Miss for a year. His defensive
coordinator moves on. He wants to
transfer, goes to Ohio State when Ryan
Day gave him a call. So durable player,
43 straight starts. And the thing that I
like is there are plays on the ball. 29
career PBUS in four seasons. That's a
fat number playing at a high level of
football against some of the best
receivers in the country. So, those are
encouraging numbers where you got to
worry a little bit. 18 penalties the
last two seasons. He's grabby and he
gets flagged. And it's clear he
developed a reputation for being grabby
because refs threw the flags on him a
good deal. Like 18 penalties in 16 were
while in coverage. I mean, that's a
problem. So, that's got to get
corrected. Um, you can be physical in
the NFL. That's a good thing. It's good
that he has that. You don't have to
coach that into him, but he's going to
have to learn the finer points of
playing physical while also not drawing
flags. That's on his to-do list.
>> Four interceptions over the last two
seasons. You mentioned that Igmanosen
fills in a depth need at cornerback. The
question being, you draft depth in the
second round. For fans who may not
understand why it's important to go that
direction in the second round,
>> how important is depth in the room right
now?
>> It's huge. And all I'll do is point to
last season.
You had Tradavius White out there who
played well in the postseason. I'm not
going to debate that for a second. He
had a nice season uh for them in his
comeback season after spending a year
away with the Rams and the Ravens. But
he gets nicked up in the Denver game.
You lose Jammarcus Ingram on a wacky
waiver situation. He's in Houston and
you have to put Dane Jackson on the
field for one play,
>> touchdown, and you lost that game in
overtime by three. You want better depth
that you can turn to. And this is no
reflection on Dane Jackson. He played
his best. Guys played his heart out when
he was in a Bills uniform, but you need
higher quality talent, especially at
quarterback in a throwing league.
Igbonosen is an example of that. Does he
have learning to do? Yes. But the elite
physical traits are there and you can
win with those and get by with those
better than a seventh round pick. They
felt they had to address it. They did it
here. Check cornerback off the list.
>> I think that's a great point by you.
It's not just depth that you're adding
to the cornerback room in Davis and
Ignosen. It is better depth. It was a
need because of what happened last year.
you felt like that position group got
really slim at times and you have
someone while he does have learning to
do can plug and play at times and does
add a physicality to the defense. We
look at who the Bills drafted 35th
overall. They go edge rusher TJ Parker
out of Clemson. Known for that power,
known for that motor, then they go
quarterback Ignosen, physicality, a
powerful type of player. What are we
learning about this 2026 draft class? uh
that they want guys that are going to
run and hit. I think that's pretty
obvious. Um these are two very
physically oriented players, players
that like to deliver a blow, I guess, is
what I'm saying. Not that there aren't
other players in this draft who can do
that, but the early indications are Jim
Leonard wants a hard-nosed
strength, powerbased,
physical defense. That's what these two
picks say to me in terms of what Jim
Leonard is looking for.
Speed might not be quite as important up
front in particular. You obviously need
speed at the corner position, but I
think players that bring a physical edge
to the field is clearly what he's
looking for based on these first two
selections on the defensive side of the
ball.
>> It seems like this coaching staff wants
players where in their head, their
mindset is we're going to be game
wreckers and we're going to impose our
force on you. We're going to make a
difference in this game. And that's kind
of what Parker and Igmanosen seem like
based on their tape and based on some of
the traits that we already talked about.
You spoke about how he matches back up
with defensive back Jordan Hancock who
played at Ohio State. Hancock and
Ignosen over overlapped for two seasons
2024 2025. Ohio State wins the natty in
2024. You're also getting a player who
plays against really good talent and
knows how to win at the highest level.
>> Yeah. And I think the thing that
encourages me is while he has to get
bigger and stronger to help a little bit
better against the run, he played in a
conference where there is a lot of
running of the football. Michigan runs
the football, Iowa runs the football,
Michigan State runs the football. Like
there's a lot of teams in that
conference. The reason that it's viewed
as something he has to work on is
because there's enough tape evidence of
him defending the run where in other
conferences, you know, out west in
particular, they throw it all over the
place. you never see a corner make a
tackle in the run front. So, he's been
exposed to it. He's still learning on
how to be better and more consistent at
it, you know, and I think with the
quarterback and DB coaches you have here
like Mike Dana, who's a good developer
of talent, Jay Valai, the new
quarterback's coach, you know, who who
enforces and prioritizes defending the
run on the edges, you know, I think he's
going to get the right coaching to get
better in that area. Buffalo had a
talented pass defense last year at the
top of the NFL. They add some new
players to the mix this year. No more
Taran Johnson. D. Alfred walks into the
building. CJ Gardner Johnson as well as
you look at the defensive backs group as
a whole. What are you learning about the
type of ball they're going to play and
how versatile it could be?
>> Yeah, I I think they want to play angry.
I mean, CJ Gardner Johnson is one of the
best trash talkers in the league, but he
brings the physicality to back it up.
Um, there are people with their head on
the swivel on offense when they're
facing CJ Gardenner Johnson cuz they
might lose their lunch um if they're not
paying attention. I think Ignosen has
that same onfield disposition. Um, maybe
he's a little quieter as a rookie, but I
think he wants to make an impact early
and often. So, while they have a lot of
good character players on this roster, I
think they wanted more players with an
edge to their game. And we we heard TJ
Parker tonight say, "When I get on the
field, I want to bring the pain." We
know how Imanosen plays. We know how CJ
Gardner Johnson plays. So, I think these
are examples of what they're trying to
institute on the defensive side of the
ball. They want an intimidation factor
on that side of the ball. So, opposing
offenses are looking over their shoulder
wondering if they're going to take an
extra lick, you know, or if they have
enough space to catch the ball and then
run or are they going to get blasted.
That goes along with one of Joe Brady's
new sayings, which is you have to play
us. It also makes sense with put the
ball down. It doesn't matter where we
play, when we play, we're going to be
ready to get after it and we're going to
play hard.